Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we have another great elementary lesson for you all.
今天我们为大家准备了另一节很棒的基础课。
That's right, we've got a lesson for all you sports fans out there.
没错，我们为所有体育迷准备了一节课。
Right, we're doing a podcast on sports today.
对，今天我们做一期关于体育的播客。
We're starting off with basketball.
我们从篮球开始。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
So we've got lots of language about basketball and sports in this lesson today.
所以今天的课程里有很多关于篮球和体育的语言。
Great, so let's take a look at our vocabulary preview.
太好了，那我们来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Two words for you today.
今天有两个词。
The first one is foul.
第一个是foul。
Foul.
Foul。
A foul.
一个犯规。
Basically, it's an action in a game that is not allowed.
基本上，这是比赛中不允许的动作。
Right, so if you're playing basketball and you kick the other player.
对，如果你打篮球时踢了另一个球员。
That's a foul.
那就是犯规。
那是犯规。
That's a pretty big foul.
那是很严重的犯规。
Yeah, if you're playing soccer and you pick up the ball.
是的，如果你踢足球时用手拿球。
That's also a foul.
那也是犯规。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Our second word is ref.
第二个词是ref。
Ref, R-E-F.
Ref，R-E-F。
Also known as a referee.
也叫做referee。
Right?
对吧？
So a referee is.
所以referee是。
Basically, like the judge of a game.
基本上，就像比赛的裁判。
The judge of the game.
比赛的裁判。
So he's the one that will.
所以他是指出。
Say that was a foul.
那是犯规的人。
That was a foul, exactly.
那是犯规，没错。
Ref, also known as referee.
Ref，也叫做referee。
Okay, so two great words.
好了，两个很棒的词。
We're gonna hear them in our dialogue and we're going to be listening to two guys who
我们会在对话中听到它们，我们将听到两个正在看电视篮球赛的家伙。
are watching a basketball game on TV.
嘿，比赛开始了吗？
Hey, has the game started yet?
Yeah, about five minutes ago.
是的，大约五分钟前。
Oh, who's winning?
哦，谁赢了？
Bulls, of course.
当然是公牛队。
What?
什么？
That wasn't a foul.
那不算犯规。
Oh, come on, ref.
哦，拜托，裁判。
Don't worry.
别担心。
Shaq always screws up free throws.
沙克罚球总是搞砸。
You were right.
你说对了。
He didn't make the shot.
他没投进。
Yeah, that was a great shot.
是啊，那球投得真漂亮。
Three pointer, yeah.
三分球，没错。
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
He traveled to the ref.
他走步了，对裁判说。
Didn't even call it.
裁判都没吹。
This ref needs glasses.
这裁判该配副眼镜了。
Hey, ref, open your eyes.
嘿，裁判，睁大你的眼睛。
Can't believe you didn't see that.
真不敢相信你没看到。
Okay, end of the first quarter.
好了，第一节结束。
All right, I'm going to make a beer run.
好吧，我去拿点啤酒。
All right, a really common situation whenever you're watching games with friends, right?
好吧，这是和朋友一起看比赛时很常见的情况，对吧？
You need to get a beer.
你需要去拿啤酒。
We'll talk about that in a little while.
我们一会儿再谈这个。
Let's take a look at language takeaway.
我们来看看语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, let's take a look at our first word on language takeaway.
好的，我们来看看语言要点的第一个词。
Free throw.
罚球。
This one's a bit hard to say, isn't it?
这个词有点难说，是吧？
It's a little bit hard to explain, but if you're playing basketball and if someone fouls
解释起来有点难，但如果你在打篮球，有人对你犯规，
you, you get a free throw.
你就会获得一次罚球。
So that's when all the players line up around you and you can throw the ball.
就是所有球员在你周围排开，你可以投篮。
To the basket without anyone blocking you or anything.
没有人阻挡你之类的。
Right.
对。
A little bit complicated, but I'm sure the basketball fans understand what a free throw
有点复杂，但我相信篮球迷们知道什么是罚球。
is.
好的，下一个词是……
All right, our next word is...
投进。
Make the shot.
投进这个球。
Let's listen to some examples and we'll understand the meaning of make the shot.
让我们听一些例子，就能理解“make the shot”的意思了。
Example one.
例子一。
I can't believe it.
我简直不敢相信。
He made the shot from the other side of the court.
他从球场另一边投进了那个球。
Example two.
例子二。
There's no way he's going to make that shot.
他不可能投进那个球的。
He's way too far away from the net.
他离网太远了。
Example three.
例子三。
If Gretzky makes this shot, they're going to win the Stanley Cup.
如果格雷茨基投进这个球，他们就会赢得斯坦利杯。
So it's clear now to make the shot is to successfully put the ball in the basket.
所以现在清楚了，“make the shot”就是成功把球投进篮筐。
You can use this expression in other sports as well, right?
这个表达也可以用在其他运动中，对吧？
Yeah, you can use it in hockey to make the shot.
是的，在冰球中可以用“make the shot”。
You could also use it in golf and a lot of different sports that use the term to shoot.
在高尔夫以及很多使用“shoot”这个术语的运动中也可以用。
Yes.
是的。
Shoot the ball.
投篮。
So anytime you shoot the ball, you can make the shot.
所以任何时候你投篮，都可以说“make the shot”。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Okay, our next word today, three pointer.
好的，我们今天的下一个词：三分球。
Three pointer.
三分球。
A three pointer.
一个三分球。
It's a shot in basketball when you get three points.
这是篮球中得三分的投篮。
Yes.
是的。
Usually this shot is taken from further out.
通常这种投篮是从更远的地方投的。
Yeah, a farther distance.
对，更远的距离。
Yeah, so it's a little bit more difficult to make this shot.
是的，所以投进这个球难度更大一些。
You know, sometimes people might say a three point shot or something like that, but our
你知道，有时候人们可能会说“three point shot”之类的，但我们的
EnglishPod learners, they know.
EnglishPod学习者都知道。
It's a three pointer.
是“three pointer”。
Yeah, you'll sound really knowledgeable, really cool using that one.
是的，用这个词会让你听起来很懂行，很酷。
Three pointer.
三分球。
And our last word today, travel.
我们今天的最后一个词：走步。
Travel.
走步。
To travel.
Travel.
走步。
When you walk with the basketball.
当你拿着篮球走路时。
Well technically, you're allowed to take two steps in basketball.
严格来说，篮球中允许走两步。
Okay.
好的。
So when you take more than two steps, then it's traveling.
所以当你走了两步以上，那就是走步。
Yes.
是的。
So yeah, traveling means to take more than two steps with the ball.
所以，走步就是指持球移动超过两步。
Let's listen to the dialogue a second time.
让我们再听一遍对话。
This time it'll be a bit slower so that we can understand some of these great phrases
这次会慢一点，这样我们就能理解一些刚才提到的
we just talked about.
精彩短语了。
Hey, has the game started yet?
嘿，比赛开始了吗？
Yeah, about five minutes ago.
嗯，大约五分钟前开始的。
Oh, who's winning?
哦，谁领先？
The Bulls, of course.
当然是公牛队。
What?
什么？
That wasn't a foul.
那不算犯规。
Oh, come on, ref.
哦，拜托，裁判。
Don't worry.
别担心。
Shaq always screws up free throws.
沙克总是罚球失误。
Yeah, you were right.
是啊，你说对了。
He didn't make the shot.
他没投进。
Yeah, that was a great shot.
是啊，那是个好球。
Three pointer, yeah.
三分球，没错。
Oh, did you see that?
哦，你看到了吗？
He traveled and the ref didn't even call it.
他走步了，裁判居然没吹。
This ref needs glasses.
这裁判需要配眼镜。
Hey, ref, open your eyes.
嘿，裁判，睁大你的眼睛。
I can't believe you didn't see that.
真不敢相信你没看到。
Okay.
好吧。
End of the first quarter.
第一节结束。
Hey, I'm going to make a beer run.
嘿，我去买点啤酒。
Sweet.
太好了。
All right, sports fans.
好了，体育迷们。
So now let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看看流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, today on Fluency Builder, we have two really common words that you would listen
好的，今天的流利度构建器中，有两个非常常见的词，你在看比赛时
to while you're watching a game.
会听到。
Yeah, these are sort of slangy words, hey?
是的，这些算是俚语词，对吧？
Yeah, they're kind of a common...
对，它们有点像是常见的……
Like informal.
非正式用语。
Informal.
非正式。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
The first one that we have is screw up.
第一个是 screw up。
Screw up.
Screw up。
To screw up.
搞砸了。
Yeah, so this is a good way of saying...
是的，这是一种很好的说法。
To make a mistake.
犯错误。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Let's listen to some examples of how this word is used.
我们来听一些这个词用法的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Jill, you really screwed up this time.
吉尔，这次你真的搞砸了。
You're fired.
你被解雇了。
Example two.
例子二。
This game is important.
这场比赛很重要。
If you screw it up, we're out of the finals.
如果你搞砸了，我们就进不了决赛了。
Example three.
例子三。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I know I screwed up.
我知道我搞砸了。
Will you forgive me?
你能原谅我吗？
Okay, so screw up is mess up.
好的，所以screw up就是mess up。
Yeah, make a mistake.
是的，犯错误。
Make a mistake.
犯错误。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Great, and our last word on Fluency Builder today, a beer run.
好的，今天Fluency Builder的最后一个词，啤酒跑。
A beer run.
啤酒跑。
Beer run.
So what is this beer run?
那么什么是啤酒跑？
You run to get beer.
你跑去买啤酒。
You go to the store and get beer.
你去商店买啤酒。
Get more beer.
买更多啤酒。
Okay, so it's just an expression meaning to go and get more beer.
好的，这只是一种表达方式，意思是去拿更多啤酒。
Yeah, usually you're watching a game or you're at home with your friends, you run out of
是的，通常你在看比赛或者和朋友在家，啤酒喝完了，所以有人得……
beer so somebody has to...
去拿些啤酒。
Go get some beer.
Make a beer run.
来个啤酒跑。
Yeah.
是的。
Hey, has the game started yet?
嘿，比赛开始了吗？
Yeah, about five minutes ago.
是的，大约五分钟前。
Who's winning?
谁领先？
Bulls, of course.
公牛队，当然。
What?
什么？
That wasn't a foul.
那不算犯规。
Oh, come on, ref.
哦，拜托，裁判。
Don't worry.
别担心。
Shaq always screws up free throws.
沙克罚球总是搞砸。
You were right.
你说得对。
He didn't make the shot.
他没投进。
Yeah, that was a great shot.
是啊，那球投得真漂亮。
Three-pointer, yeah.
三分球，没错。
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
He traveled to the ref.
他走步了，裁判就在旁边。
Didn't even call it.
居然没吹。
This ref needs glasses.
这裁判该配副眼镜了。
Hey, ref, open your eyes.
嘿，裁判，睁大你的眼睛。
I can't believe you didn't see that.
真不敢相信你没看到。
Okay, end of the first quarter.
好了，第一节结束。
All right, I'm going to make a beer run.
行，我去买趟啤酒。
Okay, guys, I hope you enjoyed our lesson today.
好了，各位，希望你们喜欢今天的课程。
We'll be bringing you more sports lessons in the future.
未来我们还会带来更多体育课程。
Yes.
是的。
So if you have a particular sport that you want to learn about, you can tell us.
所以，如果你有想了解的特定运动，可以告诉我们。
Come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Yeah, and leave us your comments or your suggestions or any doubts that you have.
对，给我们留言，提出你的意见、建议或任何疑问。
And we're always there to answer it, so we'll see you there.
我们随时会回复，所以网上见。
Yes, until next time.
是的，下次再见。
Bye.
拜拜。
Thank you.
谢谢。